MIA BORGIA

DIGITAL MEDIA, ARTS, AND DEVELOPMENT SPECIALIST

PERSONAL PROFILE

I've developed a passion to perpetually learn from the rapidly growing field of digital media, art, development, data visualization, and design. The project experiences and work opportunities I've had so far have cultivated my deep love for the digital craft.

JOB EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Engineer

LARSON TEXTS, INC. - ERIE, PA MAY 2022 - PRESENT

- Writing back-end and front-end software code to produce a software that meets or exceeds business logic and company goals for the product
- Working, collaborating, and learning with a highly skilled team of professional Front & Back-End software engineers
- Setting up a developer environment to locally host, serve, and test a complex program
- Examining and studying given code base, iterating on prior work, and making improvements to code integrity and security
- Designing a platform that is as functional and straightforward on the client side as it is "under the hood"

Raw Footage Editor

FEED STUDIO - ERIE, PA FEBRUARY 2022 - PRESENT

- Reviewing hours of raw drone footage and selectively cutting out highlight shots
- Using the client's description of desired output mood, pace, and vision for the final product to make editing decisions
- Compose the sequence of shots in a way that compliments the audio track provided by the client
- Using Adobe Premiere Pro to cut, polish, and apply transitions to selected highlight shots
- Collaborating back-and-forth with client to ensure the final cut exceeded their expectations

EDUCATION

Pennsylvania State University Erie, PA

DIGITAL MEDIA, ARTS, AND TECHNOLOGY B.A.

AUGUST 2018 - MAY 2022

Cumulative GPA: **3.83** Honors:

- Dean's List 2019-2022
- Winner of Best in Show in the Patricia Yahn Spring Art Show 2021
- Category Winner in the Patricia Yahn Spring Art Show 2022

PREVIOUS PROJECTS

- Ancient Mayans Digitized
- Blues Analysis Project
- The Ballot and Me Project
- BOLD-C Open Lab
- <u>DIGIT Program Website</u>
- Patricia Yahn Virtual Art Gallery

CONTACT ME:

814-431-8248 18 N Mill St, Apartment C - North East PA 16428 mborgia@larsontexts.com (work)

mqb5995@psu.edu (school) miamb13@gmail.com (personal)

MIA BORGIA

JOB EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

Software Development Intern

LARSON TEXTS, INC. - ERIE, PA SEPTEMBER 2021 - MAY 2022

- Writing JSON Schemas to ensure back-end data validation, uniformity, and security
- Working with and learning from a highly skilled team of professional Front & Back-End software developers and engineers
- Using ArangoDB to store, query, and graph software data
- Graph data models using XML, XSLT, and Javascript
- Collaborating with colleagues to ensure that the backend data structure conforms and reflects the company's goals and business logic
- Working with REST API development, Express.js, ArangoDB, and Postman

Web Development Intern/Creative Director & Animator

BEHREND OPEN LAB FOR DIGITAL CREATIONS (BOLDC), THE DIGIT PROGRAM AT PENN STATE ERIE DECEMBER 2020 - MAY 2022

- Creating and designing web presences for both the open lab and the DIGIT program
- Writing and styling websites with HTML, CSS, and SVG
- Helping catalogue and organize film equipment inventory
- Using Adobe Photoshop, After Effects, and Premiere Pro to create a short animated biopic film
- Creating an interactive virtual student art gallery
- Designed a logo using vector graphics in Illustrator

Back-End Data Coding Assistant

FRANKENSTEIN VARIORUM PROJECT AT PENN STATE ERIE

JUNE 2021 - MAY 2022

- Finding, assessing, and fixing bugs and coding continuity errors in a complex network of text collation code
- Writing XML, XSLT, and a bit of Python to correct data output errors

PREVIOUS PROJECTS CONTINUED

- Wintergreen Gorge Website
- What Really Happens on the Night Shift - AE Animation
- The Aquarium in Your Dreams 3D Blender Animation
- Kilgore and Kazak Character
 Animation Teaser

CONTACT ME

814-431-8248 18 N Mill St. Apartment C

18 N Mill St, Apartment C - North East PA 16428

mborgia@larsontexts.com (work) <u>mqb5995@psu.edu</u> (school) <u>miamb13@gmail.com</u> (personal)

MIA BORGIA

JOB EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

Digital Media & Coding Tutor

LEARNING RESOURCE CENTER, PENN STATE ERIE

AUGUST 2021 - MAY 2022

- Assisting other students with writing challenging code and coding syntax in various languages
- Finding personalized methods of describing digital text encoding and media concepts for each student
- Orienting students with unfamiliar and complex code software and techniques
- Working the LRC Office front desk, answering phone calls, delivering messages, scheduling tutoring meetings, and conducting other general office tasks

Website Design Intern

SUSTAINABILITY OFFICE, PENN STATE ERIE

OCTOBER 1, 2020 – JANUARY 2022

- Working with a team of interns to create a publicfacing educational website for Penn State Behrend's Wintergreen Gorge hiking trail
- Utilizing Penn State's WordPress themes to manifest the website's demo layout
- Writing creative CSS to break beyond the bounds of WordPress's limited web styling options to enhance the site's appeal
- Reviewing and adapting text content for the website to fit the Sustainability Office's vision & goals

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

Code Languages:

- HTML & CSS
- SVG
- XML
- XSLT
- XPath
- XQuery
- Relax-NG
- REGEX
- Schematron
- Python
- Javascript
- Express.js
- Node.is
- JSON
- AQL
- Angular
- SCSS (Sass)
- Typescript

Software Skills:

- Adobe Premiere Pro
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe After Effects
- Adobe Illustrator
- Meshroom
- Blender
- Unity
- oXygen XML
- Cytoscape
- Git & GitHub
- ArangoDB
- VS Code
- Jira
- eXistDB
- Postman
- Adobe XD
- Adobe Character
 Animator

CONTACT ME

814-431-8248

18 N Mill St, Apartment C - North East, PA 16428

mborgia@larsontexts.com (work) <u>mqb5995@psu.edu</u> (school) <u>miamb13@gmail.com</u> (personal)